## singlerecordnet.github.io

# José Juan Isaac Taveras Lopez

E-mail: josejuanisaac@gmail.com

### **Summary**

Software engineer experienced in database design & maintenance, data analytics & visualizations, and network security analysis. Personal philosophy centers around conducting localized research in order to produce reports that directly drive organization goals and improve operational processes. Interested in exploring the merger data aggregation design techniques and secure enterprise software development.

#### **Education**

University of Puerto Rico, Mayagüez Campus

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering (2014)

## **Training and Certifications**

- U.S. ARMY Fully Qualified as Basic Target Digital Network Analyst, Fort Meade, MD (2020)
- Army Analysis and Reporting Course, Goodfellow AFB, San Angelo, TX (2018)
- Web Development Bootcamp, DevBootcamp, San Francisco, CA (2016)

### **Work History**

#### Assistant Manager at Domino's Pizza, Winchester, Virginia

- From March 2022 to Present
- Counted full inventory daily in order to ascertain relevant information for product resupply orders which occurred 3 times a week.
- Learned to manage and supervise each store section: makeline, driver dispatch, backend office,
- Closed and opened store on a weekly basis, ensuring till and daily deposits are completed accurately and successfully,

https://singlerecordnet.github.io

Dealth with customer complaints and follow ups in order to maintain store's good standing.

#### Delivery Expert at Domino's Pizza, Winchester, Virginia

- From January 2022 to March 2022
- Completed order delivery requests, ensuring all items are accounted for and pizza ingredients match order,
- Contributed to the good working order of the store by learning all repeatable tasks

#### Target Digital Network Analyst at U.S. Army, Fort Meade, Maryland

- From 2019 to December 2021,
- Conducted target development such as open-source research and signals analysis,
- Authored and contributed to publishing several reports used by federal organizations,
- Maintained and organized documentation of collected data for presentations,
- Used network analysis tools to produce pattern-of-life visualizations,
- Collaborated in a joint military environment by developing knowledge management and project communication strategies to overcome workspace restrictions imposed by COVID-19,
- Developed browser-based tools to visualize and edit structured data sets (JSON, CSV).

#### Business Intelligence Developer as Wovenware, San Juan, Puerto Rico

- From 2014 up to 2017, stepped away for 10 months between 2015 and 2016 conducting web development bootcamp,
- Produced descriptive analytics to display aggregate user information using Qlikview BI software,
- Designed query scripts while verifying the data that was produced matched expected results,
- Performed maintenance and optimization on Qlikview backend server.

#### Rubric Solution, Manati, Puerto Rico

- Provided project-based development from 2010 to 2015,
- Designed initial SQL ER diagram and implementation using MySQL,
- Integrated Open Source chat software into underlying system and built custom group management interface,
- Implemented payment process flow with local banking provider that used XML SOAP for secure information transfer.

#### **Additional Skills and Proficiencies**

https://singlerecordnet.github.io 2/3

- Front-end: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Qlikview Dashboards, Excel
- Back-end: PHP, Ruby, Qlikview Script, MySQL
- Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, WAMP
- Languages: Native Spanish, full English, conversational French and Italian.

This site is open source. Improve this page.

https://singlerecordnet.github.io 3/3